Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Methodist, [1865-1875] (Box 30)
    Methodist churches: Mariners Church, Madison Street; Methodist church near 23rd and 4th Avenue, with Presbyterian Church in foreground, taken from the Y.M.C.A.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Orthodox, Greek/Russian, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0301
    Orthodox churches: St. John the Baptist Greek Orthodox Church, E. 17th Street; Russian Orthodox Cathedral of St. Nicholas, E. 97th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Presbyterian, [1865-1950] (Box 30)
    PR-065-0302
    Broadway Tabernacle on the N.E. corner of Broadway and 34th, Rev. Dr. Thompson; Madison Square Presbyterian Church (Dr. Charles Parkhurst), park in foreground, office building to the right; Village Presbyterian Church, W. 13th Street; Fifth Avenue Presbyterian, Dr. John Hall, minister.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Protestant Episcopal, [1865-1958] (Box 30)
    PR-065-0303
    Protestant Episcopal churches: Calvary Church, Fourth Avenue and 21st Street; Church of the Transfiguration, or Little Church Around the Corner; St. Bartholomew's (St. Barthalamus?) 44th and Madison; St. Bartholomew's Church, Park Ave. and 50th; Epiphany P.E. Church, York Ave. and 74th; Grace Church;, Broadway; St. George's Church on Stuyvesant Square, with fountain in foreground, in ruins after a fire, and rebuilt; Holy Apostles P.E. Church, 9th Ave.; St. Marks in the Bowery, 2nd Ave. and 10th; St. Paul's church and churchyard, and views from Broadway and from Vesey, including views of Astor House (residence of Thurlow Weed); St. Stephens Church, 28th near 3rd. Ave.; Trinity Church and churchyard, Broadway and Wall, including view of Alexander Hamilton Monument.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Unitarian, [1858-1875] (Box 30)
    PR-065-0304
    Dr. Belknap's church, the Church of All Souls, or "Church of the Holy Beefsteak", Fourth Avenue and 20th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Churches -- Universalist, [1870] (Box 30)
    PR-065-0305
    Church of the Divine Paternity (Dr. E.H. Chapin), corner of Fifth Avenue and 45th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Clubs, Organizations, [1868-1956] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0306
    Clubs and organizations: the Bible House, headquarters of the American Bible society; The German Society of the City of New York above an optician's shop at 13 Broadway; man standing in door of Manhattan Club House, 5th Ave. and 15th St.; Manhattan Club House, 5th Ave. and 34th Street, formerly A.T. Stewart Mansion; Masonic Temple, 23rd and 6th Avenue, designed by N. Le Brun; Union League Club, or Republican headquarters, with wrought iron balconies, 26th and Madison Ave.; University Club, 54th and Fifth Ave.; Young Men's Christian Association, 23rd and Fourth Ave., with Methodist church next door, and including an interior view of the auditorium.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Clubs, Organizations - Tammany Hall, [1868-1888] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0307
    Views of Tammany Hall, 14th Street between 3rd and Irving Place, including a view showing the building decorated with bunting and an arch decorated with greenery in front in honor of the Fourth of July; other images clearly show signs and advertisements for Bryants, and Germania Theaters, with entrance on the left side of the façade.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs., [1890-1962] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0308
    Commercial buildings: B.T. Babbitt Soap and Saleratus manufacturer, Washington Street; Bush Terminal Building, Broad, Pearl and Bridge Streets; Consolidated Edison Coal conveyors, foot of E. 38th Street; Domestic Sewing Machine building, Broadway and 14th; Painting Industry Welfare building, W. 14th Street; views in Rockefeller Center, including view looking down on skating rink, of Prometheus and of Atlas; Syndicate and St. Paul Buildings; façade of St. Paul Building, 220 Broadway; Singer and City Investing Buildings; Standard Oil Building [ca. 189-?] and Wells Building, Broadway; Gambrinus Hall and P.A. Stuber's Billiard Room, between 34th and 35th Streets; Washington Building, with elevated station in front of it, Broadway and Battery Park.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Banks, [1867-1962] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0309
    Banks: Broadway, with horse omnibuses and the Bank of the Republic; bronze doors of the Canadian Bank of Commerce, Hanover St. between Beaver St. and Exchange Street; German Savings Bank; interior view of Lockwood & Co. Banking House; Manufacturers Trust Co., 512 5th Avenue; New York Savings Bank with clock on the corner, 14th St. and 8th Ave.; façade of the Park National Bank, showing sculptural representations of Justice and Bounty.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Commodities exchanges, [1870-1954] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0310
    Commodities exchanges: The Produce exchange: 1861 building from Whitehall street; 1884 building looking down on it and Whitehall, Customs House to the right, looking along Whitehall from street level, Bowling Green to the right, views from Bowling Green; an interior view of the Produce Exchange; Cotton Exchange and elevated railroad, Hanover Square.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Drug stores, [1868-1878] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0311
    Interior view of a drug store, (in several copies) labeled variously: Gilsey House Drug Store, and Helmbold's Drug Store, Broadway.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Hotels, [1865-1957] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0312
    Hotels: Albermarle House; Astor House (home of Thurlow Weed); Brevoort House; Central Hotel and nearby businesses; Joseph Conrad's Hotel at Central Bridge, wagon out front, and theater posters on nearby wall; Coleman House, Broadway; Cumberland House, with businesses in lower floor; African-American waiters at the ready in the dining room of Earle's Hotel, corner Canal and Centre Streets; Everett House, Union Square; the Gilsey House, Broadway and 29th, with drugstore in lower floor; Grand Hotel, Broadway and 31st; Henry Bertholf's Hotel, wood-frame building with awnings over the porch, Harlem Lane; Hoffman House, Fifth Avenue and 25th;, including interior showing ornate parlor; grand staircase in the Holland House; Hotel Astor, with marquee advertising Sammy Kaye and his Orchestra; Hotel Brunswick; Hotel Holley from Washington Square; looking out the W. 72nd Street gate of Central Park at the Hotel Majestic; Hotels Netherland and Savoy, showing trolley tracks running up the street between them; the Lafarge House and Broadway; New York Hotel, with Gurney's Gallery to the left; St. James Hotel, Broadway; St. Nicholas Hotel, Broadway, Spring and Broome Sts., including interior view of dining room; Springler House, with a Saloon, a Ladies Hair Store and other businesses in lower floors, men in top-hats on the stoop; Stewart's Hotel for Female Operatives; Tammany Hall and Hotel; Union Square Hotel, with organ and piano stores next door, taken from the Domestic Sewing Machine Co.; Village Hotel, 154 Bleecker Street; Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, with street thronged with traffic; carriage in front of the Washington Hotel; Windsor Hotel, Fifth Ave. and 46th St., including an interior view of the dining room.
    57 items
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Hotels -- Fifth Avenue, [1865-1895] (Box 30)
    Identifier: PR-065-0313
    Fifth Avenue Hotel, Fifth Avenue and 23rd, showing surrounding areas, including an edge of Madison Square Park and streets with wagons and trolleys, and an interior view of the dining room.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Hotels -- Grand Central, [1865-1885] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0314
    The Grand Central Hotel, Broadway near Bond, where Jim Fisk was killed; Southern hotel to the north with advertisement for the "European Plan", and the Tremont House and "J. M. Morrow Microscopic Pictures" to the south.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Hotels -- Grand Union, [1874-1889] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0315
    Grand Union Hotel, 4th Avenue and 42nd Street, near Grand Central Station, some views showing carriages lined up along Fourth (Park) Avenue.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Insurance buildings, [1875-1954] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0316
    Insurance Company buildings: Equitable Building; Knickerbocker Insurance Co.'s building; Manhattan Life and Security Building, opposite Trinity Church; Metropolitan Life building with clock tower, and Dr. Parkhurst's Madison Square Church on Madison Square Park; the North building of Met Life, from Madison Square Park; N.Y. Life Insurance Building, Broadway and Leonard St.; New York Life's building on Madison, Park, 26th and 27th Sts. From Madison Square Park, and looking through the backyards of buildings from the 28th St. station of the 3rd Ave. elevated train.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Markets, [1875-1956] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0317
    Markets: Commuter's Market, Vesey and West Broadway, with plants and flowers in front of a nursery, and a hardware store on the corner; Men and boxes of fish in front of the Fulton Fish Market, street vendor selling hot franks to the right; view labeled Manhattan Market, but may be another in Cooper Square; empty interior of the Manhattan Market; cars in front of the Washington Market, West Street, Fulton to Vesey.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Photography studios, [1859] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0318
    E. Anthony's photography studio at 501 Broadway.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Publishing, [1865-1954] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0319
    Newspaper and magazine publishers: Harper's Publishing House; the Herald building on Broadway; people reading the war bulletins on the front of the New York Journal building from City Hall Park; man buying newspaper from boy while others read bulletin on the front of the Evening Post building; the Staats-Zeitung, Centre Street across from City Hall, with one view showing building decked out with bunting, flags and a portrait of a visiting dignitary; the Times building downtown in Printer's Row, with signs for advertising agencies, and a view of an uptown building with the elevated railroad in the foreground; the Tribune Tower, with clock tower, including view from the New Post Office and the park, with fountain in foreground; the old World building near the old Times building, and the New World Building across from City Hall, including views with City Hall in the view at the left, one with the tower of the Brooklyn Bridge in the distance, and a view showing street full of trolleys and of people reading the bulletins about the Spanish American War posted on the front of the building.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Restaurants and taverns, [1870-1963] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0320
    Restaurants and taverns: Cavanagh's 258 W. 23, showing decorative ironwork and lighted signs; Delmonico's, 14th and 5th Avenue; Fraunces Tavern, Pearl and Broad Streets; 13th Street end of Lüchow's Restaurant; awnings and signs of the Press Box Restaurant, Steak Row and Cheval Blanc in 45th, E. of Lexington; the Peacock, view of the door, and a carved peacock in the window; Pony Bar with entry in shape of a smile, and faux wheels attached to the wall, 150 W. 4th Street; the 21 Club, with jockey statuette hitching posts lining steps and balcony; Scheffel hall and Joe King's Rathskeller, 3rd. Ave. and 17th St. Werderman's Hall, 156-60 3rd Ave. with signs for dining, dancing, meeting room and bowling alley; Ye Olde Firehouse Tavern, 1326 Cedar Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Shops, exteriors, [1860-1957] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0321
    Shops, exteriors: H. B. Claflin & Co. Dry Goods Store, 34-62 Worth Street; Fay-Ward Cowboy Tailors, above Pierre au Tunnel French Restaurant on W. 48th; Lord and Taylor's Store, Broadway and 20th, showing cast iron front; dapper men pose in entrance of Olipaht and Gilday Clothiers and Merchant Tailors, in Lovejoys Hotel at 31 Park Row, 1863-1869; A. T. Stewart's store, Broadway to Fourth Ave, between 9th and 10th.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Shops, interiors, [1865-1885] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0322
    Interior views of shops: display case at the American Clock Co., 3 Cortland St.; interior of E. Anthony's Stereoscopic Emporium [copy]; chandeliers and gas fixtures on the third floor, and a display of silver with two busts of women, at Ball, Black & Co.; long case of watches, a woman and salesmen, Benedict Brothers Store, Broadway and Cortlandt St.; Berrian House furnishing warerooms, with chairs, baskets and other goods; Rufus M. Brundige, china, gas fixtures, plated ware, vases and other goods; Francis Freeman, musical boxes, clocks, bronzes; George A. Jones & Co., clocks; Hillyer, Mackay & Co., Hosiery warehouse, showing boxes and stacks of goods; John Horton & Co. showroom with gas fixtures; C.A. Stevens & Co., Jewelers and Silversmiths; Studebaker Bros. Carriage showroom, with man sitting in carriage hitched to life-sized wooden horse; proprietor and salesmen around the edge of the display area, Wilson, Yale and Staats, notions hosiery, white goods, etc.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Stock exchanges, [1870-1965] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0323
    Stock Exchanges: New York Stock Exchange on Broad Street, one view with group of men in front; another building identified only as stock exchange; façade of the George Post Stock Exchange building, showing the J.Q.A. Ward pediment sculpture.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Empire State, 1954-1957 (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0324
    Empire State Building: view from the Crane Co. showroom, with map painted on the showroom window super-imposed on the Empire State Building; east from subway stairs, 34th and 7th Avenue; looking up at the mooring mast from the 86th floor.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Flatiron Building, [1900-1925] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0325
    Flatiron building: looking at point of building from a building to the north, Fifth Ave., Broadway, and the edge of Madison Square; from the street level looking south down Fifth Ave.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Western Union Building, [1870-1889] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0326
    Western Union Building, Broadway, showing nearby buildings on Fulton and Broadway, and the building's clock tower.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Commercial bldgs. -- Woolworth Building, [1913-1940] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0327
    Woolworth building: two views form high vantages, one from the Singer Building, one from the S.E.; view from City Hall Park.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs., [1870-1960] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0328
    Government and public buildings: New York State Arsenal, 7th Avenue and 35th Street; 37th Regiment Armory, 6th Avenue and Broadway, with grocery wagon in front; 71st Regiment Armory, Park Avenue and 33rd; the Custom House; New York Coliseum; Jefferson Market Courthouse; Municipal Asphalt plant; General Post Office, 8th Avenue.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Castle Clinton, [1865-1915] (Box 31)
    Identifier: PR-065-0329
    Castle Clinton, or Castle Garden, also the Aquarium: views from Battery Park, and from high vantages showing the park, Castle Clinton, traffic in the harbor, and Liberty Statue, group of men standing in front of the building when it was an emigrant landing depot; group, including a police officer, in the park in front of the building; views from the water showing the buildings of lower Manhattan beyond; view of one of the doors; William Jennings Bryan arriving at the pier at Castle Garden, and being driven through crowd in front of it.
    38 items
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- City Hall, [1850-1954] (Box 32)
    Identifier: PR-065-0330
    City Hall, City Hall Park, the Municipal building and surrounding buildings, including the World building; statue of Nathan Hale with City Hall in the background; view of City Hall with the Woolworth Building looming over it.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Forts, not Clinton, [1865-1889] (Box 32)
    Identifier: PR-065-0331
    Forts other than Castle Clinton: Fort Lafayette, in the narrows between Staten Island and Brooklyn, used as prison during the Civil War; soldiers next to wall of fort; Castle William, Governor's Island.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Hall of Records, [1865-1925] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0332
    Hall of Records: the old Hall of Records at the Junction of Chatham and Centre Streets, view from Printing House Square showing horse omnibuses and foot traffic, and street level view showing pedestrians, and Records building to the left; New Hall of Records or Surrogate's Court Building on Chambers Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Hospitals, [1850-1963] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0333
    Hospitals: Bellevue Hospital, 1st Avenue; Columbia-Presbyterian Hospital from Riverside Park; New York Hospital, Broadway between Duane and Worth Streets; New York Hospital, York Avenue and 68th Street; views of a hospital, labeled both Presbyterian and Lenox Hospital, 73rd, between Fourth and Madison [see also under Institutions, Episcopal Home]; Roosevelt Hospital, 9th Avenue and 59th Street.; St. Luke's Hospital, 5th Avenue and 54th Street; St. Matthews Hospital, Lexington Avenue and 42nd Street; New York State Women's Hospital, Fourth Avenue and 50th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Institutions, 1861-1951 (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0334
    Institutions: The Blind Asylum; buildings on Blackwell's Island; the Episcopal Home [see also under Hospitals]; the Five Points Mission, including interior view of chapel; House of Industry at Five Points; Greenwich Village Humane League Shop, one view showing bucket for watering horses out front; Orphan or Foundling Asylum, on 68th Street; views at the Colored Orphan Asylum taken Good Friday, 1861: girls in the courtyard with hoops, children ranged around the edge of a classroom, two teachers in the center, boys in a dormitory room; children in the yard of Home for the Friendless, man in top-hat at the rear, laundry hanging overhead.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Post Office, Broadway, [1869-1890] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0335
    Old, or Nassau Street Post Office, including view looking up Nassau from Wall showing pedestrian traffic.
    41 items
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Post Office, Nassau St., [1866] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0336
    New Post Office, on Broadway in City Hall Park: construction views, including early view showing foundations and first course with City Hall beyond; views showing the building looking down on the point of Broadway and Printing House Square, some views showing traffic on Broadway, including trolleys, and a view of pedestrians in the foreground; views from the back, including view showing edge of park, and wagons pulled up to the building; interior views.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Tombs, Old, [1865-1896] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0337
    Views of the Tombs House of Detention: primarily views of the new-Egyptian front of the building, and including a view of the "Bridge of sighs" connecting the prison to the court building across the street, and views of the interior courtyards and walkways.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- Treasury, [1860-1951] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0338
    Views of the United States Sub-treasury, or Customs house: views along the Wall Street, from Nassau Street, and including the J.Q.A. Ward sculpture of Washington.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Gov't and Public Bldgs. -- United Nations, 1951-1954 (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0339
    United Nations: construction views from 41st and 42nd streets, with Queensboro Bridge in background; sun reflecting off of flat tower, taken from 47th and 1st Ave.; U.N. from between the buildings on 43rd Street, trees and light fixture in the foreground; Assembly Hall and flags.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Libraries, [1865- 1963] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0340
    Libraries: Astor Library, later the Public Theater, including interior; Mercantile Library Association Building, Clinton Hall, on Astor Place; Morgan Library entrance, 29 E. 36th; the New York Public Library at 5th Ave. and 42nd Street, showing lion, including one with wreath, from across Fifth Ave., and the terrace with 500 fifth Avenue building in the background.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums, [1865-1961] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0341
    Museums: Woods Museum at Broadway and 30th; 77th Street entrance, and Roosevelt (Central Park West) entrance to the American Museum of Natural History, including view of the Roosevelt statue; the sculpture El Cid in front of the Hispanic Society.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- Barnum's, [1868-1875] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0342
    Barnum's Museum, on lower Broadway, coated with ice after the fire that destroyed it, March, 1868; Barnum's Roman Hippodrome, formerly Union Depot, Fourth Avenue, 26th to 27th Streets, including interior view showing ring and stands.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- Cloisters, 1949 (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0343
    The Cloisters Museum: from the South, Fort Tyron Park; the tower, tower and entrance with grate; the cloisters and the gardens.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- Guggenheim, 1958-1961 (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0344
    Guggenheim Museum, Fifth Avenue and 89th; views of the museum under construction with scaffolding and fences; from Fifth Avenue below 88th; interior view: two women looking at abstract expressionist painting.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- Metropolitan, [1870-1961] (Box 32)
    Identifier:PR-065-0345
    Metropolitan Museum of Art: early view showing sky-lights in the roof; the museum in the park, including view of park goers strolling and in a buggy; Fifth Avenue façade.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- Museum of the City of New York, 1958 (Box 33)
    Identifier: PR-065-0346
    Museum of the City of New York, from Fifth Avenue.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Museums -- New-York Historical Society, [1865-1961] (Box 33)
    Identifier: PR-065-0347
    The New-York Historical Society: the building at 2nd Avenue and 11th Street, with Tabernacle Baptist Church to the right; case of photographs and artifacts at the Fiftieth Anniversary Subway exhibit; building at 77th and Central Park West from the N.E.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Residences -- Apartment houses, [1884-1960] (Box 33)
    Identifier: PR-065-0348
    Apartment houses: the Dakota, from the S.E. near Central Park West; Manhattan Towers, Third Ave. and 65th; Osborne Flats, 205 W. 57th Street; San Remo Apartments from the S.W. with row houses and parking lot in the foreground; Sheridan Arms Apartments on Sheridan Square, with large sign advertising its imminent demolition; Tudor City from 40th Street between 1st and 2nd Avenues; earliest apartments at 142 East 18th.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Residences -- Houses and homes, exterior, [1865-1957] (Box 33)
    Identifier:PR-065-0349